Prepare for a giant adventure
Jack the Giant Slayer is a fantasy, action,
adventure film directed by Bryan Singer.
The story of an ancient war that is reignited when a young farmhand unwittingly
opens a gateway between our world and a fearsome race of giants.
Unleashed on the Earth for the first time in centuries, the giants strive to reclaim the land they
once lost, forcing the young man, Jack into the battle of his life to stop them.
Fighting for a kingdom, its people, and the love of a brave princess, he comes face to face with the
unstoppable warriors he thought only existed in legend–and gets the chance to become a legend himself.
Jack, played by Nicholas Hoult.
Princess Isabelle, played by Eleanor Tomlinson.
Elmont, played by Ewan McGregor.
Roderick, played by Stanley Tucci.
King Brahmwell, played by Ian McShane.
General Fallon, played by Bill Nighy.
Jack the Giant Slayer (previously titled Jack the Giant Killer) is a 2013 American fantasy adventure film directed by Bryan
Singer and written by Darren Lemke, Christopher McQuarrie and Dan Studney, from a story by Lemke and David Dobkin.
The film, based on the British fairy tales "Jack the Giant Killer" and "Jack and the Beanstalk", stars
Nicholas Hoult, Eleanor Tomlinson, Stanley Tucci, Ian McShane, Bill Nighy, and Ewan McGregor.
The film tells the story of Jack, a young farmhand who must save a captured princess from a race of giants after
accidentally opening a gateway to their land in the sky while also contending with a crooked lord.
Development of Jack the Giant Slayer began in 2005,
when Lemke first pitched the idea.
Caruso was hired to direct the film in January 2009, but in September of that year, Caruso
was replaced by Singer, who hired McQuarrie and Studney to rework the script.
The main characters were cast between February and March 2011, and principal photography began in
April 2011 in England with locations in Somerset, Gloucestershire and Norfolk.
The release of the film was moved back in post-production to
allow more time for visual effects and marketing.
Jack the Giant Slayer premiered on February 26, 2013, in Hollywood.
It was released theatrically in the United States on March 1, 2013, receiving mixed reviews from critics and
was a box-office failure, earning $197 million worldwide against a budget of $185–200 million.
The film explores themes of nostalgic, based on fairy tale, giant.
The tone is emotional.